The Reese Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- The Stevens Family, 1721 - 1856; 4; Box: 27 Folders: 1 - 9
  - Francis Kerby Stevens, 1885 - 1945; 4.9; Boxes: 51 - 55 Folders: 14 - 21, 1 - 25, 1 - 20, 1 - 10 - 17, 1 - 8
    - Personal correspondence, 1895 - 1945; 4.9.1; Boxes: 51 - 53 Folders: 14 - 21, 1 - 25, 1 - 6
      - Christmas cards from cousins to “Uncle Francis” (Francis Kerby Stevens), undated (Folder 11, Box 52)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Robert Shaw Oliver regarding health of baby Elizabeth, undated (Folder 12, Box 52)
      - Letter to Elizabeth Shaw Oliver Stevens (Bessie) from Francis Kerby Stevens describing Christmas Day hunt, presented to the Essex Hunt Club in 1947 by Mrs. Stevens, 1907 (Folder 13, Box 52)
      - Two letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his mother, Mary (Alleyne) Otis Stevens, one is an Easter card, both written from Bermuda, 1907 (Folder 14, Box 52)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens likely from his cousin Louis Gallatin. The letter is from Switzerland and refers to his engagement., circa 1907 (Folder 15, Box 52)
      - Ten letters to Francis Kerby Steven from his wife, Elizabeth Shaw Oliver Stevens from Murray Bay, Canada to Lawrence, Long Island. The letter refers to the baby Elizabeth., circa 1908 (Folder 16, Box 52)
      - Nine letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his mother, Mary (Alleyne) Otis Stevens from Bermuda where she spends the winter, 1907 December - 1908 April (Folder 17, Box 52)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Nora Hutchison congratulating him on his marriage, 1908 May 25 (Folder 18, Box 52)
      - Two letters to Frances Stevens Reese from her father Francis Kerby Stevens while she was attending boarding school in Virginia. Two additional letters written after she was married. The one dated July was sent to her in France and the second is sent to her in New Haven, Connecticut, 1933, 1937 (Folder 19, Box 52)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Corrine Douglas Robinson, referring to her announced engagement, circa 1907 (Folder 20, Box 52)
      - Two letters between Lambert Valle and Francis Kerby Stevens, Valle has enlisted in the war and Stevens’s letters recall his experiences in the Spanish War, 1942 (Folder 21, Box 52)
      - Letter to “Uncle Francis” regarding the wedding of BK Stevens in Annapolis, Maryland, 1943 June 13 (Folder 22, Box 52)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Duke of Roxburghe, UK, undated (Folder 23, Box 52)
      - Nine wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England [some parts of letters cut out by British sensors], 1940 (Folder 24, Box 52)
      - Six wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England [some parts of letters cut out by British sensors], 1940 (Folder 25, Box 52)
      - Four wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England, 1940 (Folder 1, Box 53)
      - Seven wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England and letter from her landlord [?], with photograph in File 8.3.72.49, 1941 (Folder 2, Box 53)
      - Two wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England, 1942 (Folder 3, Box 53)
      - Four wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England, 1943 (Folder 4, Box 53)
      - Two wartime letters to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England, 1944 (Folder 5, Box 53)
      - A wartime letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from his niece, Mary Swan on the Isle of Wight, England, 1945 (Folder 6, Box 53)
    - Business correspondence, 1922 - 1943; 4.9.2; Box: 53 Folders: 7 - 14
      - Correspondence regarding the Eternity Fish and Game Club in Quebec. There are four letters between Francis Stevens and Elliot James regarding membership in the club as well as a club report, 1922, 1923 (Folder 7, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Robert Winthrop regarding securities, 1938 December 30 (Folder 8, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Chateau Murray Bay Hotel (letter is in French), 1930 June 28 (Folder 9, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from Joseph Couturier of La Mal Baie, regarding a trip to Quebec, 1940 July 27 (Folder 10, Box 53)
      - Letter from the Directors of the Plaza Hotel with annual directors stipend of $150.00, 1945 January 10 (Folder 11, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from the Sons of the Revolution offering membership on the real estate committee, 1944 December (Folder 12, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens from H.A. Wexler regarding the Stevens family vault at Greenwood Cemetery, 1943 January (Folder 13, Box 53)
      - Letter to Francis Kerby Stevens allowing him increased gas rations, 1943 January 16 (Folder 14, Box 53)
    - Business Materials, 1908 - 1944; 4.9.3; Boxes: 53 - 54 Folders: 15 - 20, 1 - 4
      - Documents regarding the purchase of the Stevens home on 61 East 92nd St in New York. Documents include an electrical inspection certificate, house insurance, sale contract, list of building restrictions, real estate appraisal and title., 1921 (Folder 15, Box 53)
      - Journal of the American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers with article by Francis Kerby Stevens (also two typed copies), 1933 April (Folder 16, Box 53)
      - Real Estate appraisal of properties by Francis Kerby Stevens for the Hackensack Water Company (bound book), undated (Folder 17, Box 53)
      - New York City Building Zone Restrictions, 1920 (Folder 18, Box 53)
      - Account book, Astor Trust Company Account, 1908 - 1911 (Folder 19, Box 53)
      - Court Documents with the testimony of Francis Kerby Stevens as a witness on behalf of a realtor, 1944 (Folder 20, Box 53)
      - Expense account, 1919 - 1922 (Folder 1, Box 54)
      - Testimony of Francis K. Stevens as witness for Real Estate case, 1942 December 16 (Folder 2, Box 54)
      - Blank checks, Banque Canadienne Nationale, undated (Folder 3, Box 54)
      - Francis Kerby Stevens account with Robert Winthrop, 1934 (Folder 4, Box 54)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 - 1945; 4.9.4; Box: 54 Folders: 5 - 9
      - Article announcing the change of the company name to include Stevens. Company known as Brown, Whitlock, Harris and Stevens, 1936 June 21 (Folder 5, Box 54)
      - Article titled “Stevens shows relationship of rent and value”, 1942 April 19 (Folder 6, Box 54)
      - New York Times article, “Realty Appraisals”, 1929 November 17 (Folder 7, Box 54)
      - New York Times obituary of Francis Kerby Stevens, two copies, 1945 August 19 (Folder 8, Box 54)
      - “Stevens urges Steps to Save Realty in New York City,” New York Times article, 1943 February 14 (Folder 9, Box 54)
    - Miscellany, 1885 - 1945; 4.9.5; Boxes: 54 - 55 Folders: 10 - 17, 1 - 8
      - Bound book titled Yale Humor. The inscription is Miss Stevens, Yale sophomore, German, circa 1890s (Folder 10, Box 54)
      - Blue ribbon labeled real estate with a medal attached. The medal is labeled Citizens Preparedness Parade. There is also a blue satin sash labeled Major, Real Estate, 1916 May 13 (Folder 11, Box 54)
      - Certificate from the Secretary of the Treasury to Francis Stevens for his support of the 1919 Victory Liberty Loan, circa 1919 (Folder 12, Box 54)
      - Grocery bill, Montreal, the groceries were likely intended for a fishing trip in Quebec, 1920 August 18 (Folder 13, Box 54)
      - Single loose-leaf sheet titled Christmas hymn. In a child’s writing is the first verse of Hark the Herald Angels Sing and it is signed Merry Christmas to Daddy from Frances, circa 1920s (Folder 14, Box 54)
      - New York State Society of Real Estate Appraisers Certificate, bill for $10 annual fee, 1941 (Folder 15, Box 54)
      - Bound folder offering condolences to the family of Francis Kerby Stevens following his death, from the Plaza Hotel where he was a director, 1945 August (Folder 16, Box 54)
      - Bound folder offering condolences to the family of Francis Kerby Stevens following his death, from the New York Real Estate Board, 1945 August (Folder 17, Box 54)
      - Memorabilia. Story with sketches by Frances Stevens for her father Francis, titled “A Wee Drop of Scotch”, undated (Folder 1, Box 55)
      - Reminiscences of Francis Kerby Stevens by his daughter Frances Stevens Reese, 11 pages, undated (Folder 2, Box 55)
      - Lock of hair of Francis Kerby Stevens, 1885 (Folder 3, Box 55)
      - Report Cards from the Sheffield School at Yale, 1896 - 1897 (Folder 4, Box 55)
      - Invitation to Francis Stevens to attend the Second Assembly, undated (Folder 5, Box 55)
      - Discharge certificate from the army, undated (Folder 6, Box 55)
      - Various identification cards, undated (Folder 7, Box 55)
      - Death certificate of Francis Kerby Stevens, 1945 (Folder 8, Box 55)
- The Davie Family, 1914 - 1976; 5; Box: 56 Folders: 1 - 18
  Series contains materials pretaining to Eugenia (May) Ladenburg Davie and Newspaper Clippings
  - Eugenie (May) Ladenburg Davie, 1914 - 1976; 5.1; Box: 56 Folders: 1 - 16
    - Letters to Mary (May) Otis Stevens from Eugenie (May) Ladenburg Davie, including articles and debates, 1940 - 1941 (Folder 1, Box 56)
    - Letter to Mary (May) Otis Stevens with enclosed copy of the address made by May Davie at the Luncheon of the Women’s Division, United Republican Finance Committee, circa 1944 (Folder 2, Box 56)
    - Transcript of May Davie’s broadcast on WABC, sent to Mary (May) Otis Stevens, 1941 September 11 (Folder 3, Box 56)
    - Letter to Mary (May) Otis Stevens telling of May Davie’s resignation from the A.W.V.J. and containing the reports she submitted at the last board meeting, 1942 February 19 (Folder 4, Box 56)
    - Letter to Mary (May) Otis Stevens with newspaper clipping of Thomas E. Dewey Speech and transcript of May Davie’s speech, 1948 October 30 (Folder 5, Box 56)
    - Speeches and Radio transcripts by May Davie, undated (Folder 6, Box 56)
    - Diary of Elizabeth Stevens Ladenburg, mother of May Davie, sister of Francis Kerby Stevens, undated (Folder 7, Box 56)
    - Trust Accounts of Eugenie Mary Ladenburg, 1916 (Folder 8, Box 56)
    - Address Book, 1921 (Folder 9, Box 56)
    - Awards Received, various (Folder 10, Box 56)
    - Bill from Byrnes& Lowery Freight Forwarders for One Case Tapestry, 1921 (Folder 11, Box 56)
    - Program flyer for Thomas Dewey campaign rally sent to Miss Stevens, 1944 October 30 (Folder 12, Box 56)
    - Gettysburg Address - 1940 edition Anti-New Deal propaganda, circa 1940 (Folder 13, Box 56)
    - Homemade book - “Saga of a Great Injustice”, 1966 August (Folder 14, Box 56)
    - A Birthday Greeting from Elizabeth Mitchell to May Davie, copy sent to Miss Stevens, 1944 January 31 (Folder 15, Box 56)
    - Correspondence between Frances Stevens Reese and Count Leopold Franciszek Chodkiewicz concerning the address of May Ladenburg Davie, circa 1976 (Folder 16, Box 56)
    - Newspaper clippings, 5.1.1; Box: 56 Folders: 17 - 18
      - Newspaper clippings, various (Folder 17, Box 56)
      - Newspaper clippings, various (Folder 18, Box 56)
- The Rathbone Family, 1840 - 1903; 6; Boxes: 57 - 58 Folders: 1 - 14, 1 -22
  Series contains materials pretaining to John Finely Rathbone and Marion Rathbone Oliver.
  - John Finley Rathbone, 1840 - 1903; 6.1; Boxes: 57 Folders: 1 - 7
    - Writing by John Rathbone, with two carbon copies, 1840 January 7 (Folder 1, Box 57)
    - Letters to John Rathbone from daughter, Marion Rathbone, circa 1861 - 1864 (Folder 2, Box 57)
    - Letters to John Rathbone from daughter, Marion Rathbone and granddaughter Bessie (Elizabeth Shaw Oliver), circa 1891 - 1900 (Folder 3, Box 57)
    - Correspondence, 1853 (Folder 4, Box 57)
    - Correspondence, 1863 (Folder 5, Box 57)
    - Written Psalms given to John Rathbone by Bishop Doani [?] after the sechnese [?] of Dairy Doani of Lenox, 1879 September 15 (Folder 6, Box 57)
    - John Rathbone Memorial Program (book), circa 1901 (Folder 7, Box 57)
  - Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1860 - 1936; 6.2; Boxes: 57 - 58 Folders: 8 - 14, 1 - 22
    - Large collection of letters from Marion Rathbone to her parents, circa 1860s (Folder 8, Box 57)
    - Letters to Marion Rathbone from her sister, Lucy, undated (Folder 9, Box 57)
    - Letters from John Rathbone Oliver (Jack, Jon) to his parents, Robert Shaw Oliver and Marion Rathbone Oliver, some from Cambridge and London, circa 1883 - 1892 (Folder 10, Box 57)
    - Two letters from John Rathbone to Marion Rathbone, 1890 (Folder 11, Box 57)
    - Two letters to Marion Rathbone from her daughter, Cora Lyman Oliver, undated (Folder 12, Box 57)
    - Collection of letters to Marion Rathbone from her daughter, Elizabeth Shaw Oliver (Bessie), addressed to either “mother” or “family”, circa 1894 (Folder 13, Box 57)
    - Large collection of letters from Marion Rathbone Oliver to her children, circa 1895 (Folder 14, Box 57)
    - Large collection of letters from Marion Rathbone Oliver to her children, circa 1895 (Folder 1, Box 58)
    - Collection of letters written to Marion Rathbone Oliver’s daughter, Cora Lyman Oliver, from her mother, siblings and Joseph Choate whom she would later marry, circa 1890s (Folder 2, Box 58)
    - Collection of letters to Marion Rathbone from her daughter, Elizabeth Shaw Oliver (Bessie), addressed to either “mother” or “family”, 1895 - 1896 (Folder 3, Box 58)
    - Four Letters to Marion Rathbone Oliver from First Lady Edith Kermit Roosevelt, undated (Folder 4, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from Helen H. Taft (Folder 5, Box 58)
    - Two letters from brother, Franny B.[?], 1866 - 1870 (Folder 6, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver, undated (Folder 7, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from Lena Pist [?], 1889 (Folder 8, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from A. Pepperthorn [?], 1892 (Folder 9, Box 58)
    - Letter of recommendation for Marion Rathbone Oliver for her trip abroad with Letter in French from the Belgian embassy, 1910 (Folder 10, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from Harris Lagercraut, 1910 December 11 (Folder 11, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from S.K.R., 1913 (Folder 12, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from Robert F. Leurry [?], undated (Folder 13, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from S.K.R., undated (Folder 14, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from her daughter, Marion L. Oliver, 1936 October 4 (Folder 15, Box 58)
    - Letter to Marion Rathbone Oliver from her daughter, Marion L. Oliver, undated (Folder 16, Box 58)
    - Letter to Elizabeth Oliver Stevens (Bessie) from her cousin, Ned Bowditch with the American Expeditionary Force concerning Marion Rathbone Oliver with pictures from the Philippines, contained photographs in File 8.5.72.82, 1918 October (Folder 17, Box 58)
    - Funeral Cards for Mary A. Rathbone, 1902 January 26 (Folder 18, Box 58)
    - Poem with Mary Rathbone Oliver’s initials, 1889 July 23 (Folder 19, Box 58)
    - Newspaper article on the wedding of Miss Grace Rathbone, undated (Folder 20, Box 58)
    - Card from Elizabeth Oliver Stevens (Bessie) to her mother, Marion Rathbone Oliver, undated (Folder 21, Box 58)
    - Marion Oliver, Book of Her Spiritual Pilgrimage, likely Marion L. Oliver, 1919 - 1936 (Folder 22, Box 58)
- The Oliver Family, 1839 - 1943; 7; Boxes: 59 - 69 Folders: 1 - 37, 1 - 9, 1 - 19, 1 - 16, 1 - 23, 1 - 18, 1 - 11, 1 - 16, 1 - 21, 1 - 27
  Series contains materials pretaining to Daniel and Elizabeth Oliver, Robert Shaw Oliver, Elizabeth Shaw Oliver Stevens, and John Rathbone Oliver
  - Daniel Augustus Oliver and Elizabeth Shaw Oliver, 1839 - 1850; 7.1; Box: 59 Folders: 1 - 21
    - Letter from Robert Shaw Oliver to his daughter Elizabeth (“Bessie”) Shaw Oliver concerning the papers of his parents, Daniel Augustus Oliver and Elizabeth (Willard) Shaw Oliver, undated (Folder 1, Box 59)
    - Letter from Daniel A. Oliver concerning the birth of his son, 1847 (Folder 2, Box 59)
    - Three letters written by Elizabeth Shaw to Caroline Healey, 1829, 1841 (Folder 3, Box 59)
    - Three letters in Elizabeth Shaw’s handwriting, one is to Harriet Sturgis, undated (Folder 4, Box 59)
    - Letter to Hatty (Harriet Sturgis) from Elizabeth Shaw, circa 1840s (Folder 5, Box 59)
    - Two Letters to Hatty (Harriet Sturgis from Elizabeth Shaw concerning the death of a friend, 1843 May 16, 29 (Folder 6, Box 59)
    - Letter to her father, Robert Gould Shaw from Elizabeth Shaw Oliver from Brattleboro, Vermont. The letter mentions little Robbie (Robert Shaw Oliver) is recovering well, 1848 (Folder 7, Box 59)
    - Letter to Elizabeth Shaw from her brother from Alexandria, Egypt, detailing his travels, observations and poor health, 1849 December 3 (Folder 8, Box 59)
    - Letter to Daniel Oliver from his friend, Charles regarding the death of Elizabeth Shaw, there is also a small unsigned note of condolence and a dried cherry leaf, 1850 March 8 (Folder 9, Box 59)
    - Letter from Daniel Oliver with itemized expenses, 1850 February 11 (Folder 10, Box 59)
    - Two letters of Robert Gould Shaw, to Jacob Townsley and Persis Lewis, 1846, 1850 (Folder 11, Box 59)
    - Letter to Robbie (Robert Shaw Oliver) from his nurse Bridget (Bindy), circa 1849 (Folder 12, Box 59)
    - Six folded papers dated on the day Elizabeth Shaw Oliver died, 2 contain dried flowers and the others locks of hair, from Lizzie, Robert Shaw and Frank Shaw (died 1849), 1850 February 14 (Folder 13, Box 59)
    - Funeral expenses for the funeral of Elizabeth Shaw Oliver, mentions she is buried at Mt. Auburn cemetery, 1850 (Folder 14, Box 59)
    - Name Card of Daniel A. Oliver, undated (Folder 15, Box 59)
    - Certificate states that Elizabeth Shaw passed under Niagara Falls, 1839 (Folder 16, Box 59)
    - 18 Recipes in the handwriting of Elizabeth Shaw, circa 1840 (Folder 17, Box 59)
    - Five recipes labeled “Miss Pollocks”, undated (Folder 18, Box 59)
    - Two recipes for muffins and a delicate cake, undated (Folder 19, Box 59)
    - Five page manuscript titled, “History of our Savior”, undated (Folder 20, Box 59)
    - Letter from Lizzie to Harriet Sturgis, undated (Folder 21, Box 59)
  - Robert Shaw Oliver, 1887 - 1935; 7.2; About X linear feet Boxes: 59 - 63 Folders: 22 - 37, 1 - 9, 1 - 19, 1 - 16, 1 - 6
    Series contains correspondence and miscellany
    - Correspondence, 1873 - 1911; 7.2.1; Boxes: 59 - 61 Folders: 22 - 37, 1 - 9, 1 - 15
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1873 (Folder 22, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1874 (Folder 23, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1877 (Folder 24, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1878 (Folder 25, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, 1903 (Folder 26, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to wife, Marion Rathbone Oliver, undated (Folder 27, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to son, John Rathbone Oliver, 1889 (Folder 28, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to son, John Rathbone Oliver, 1890 (Folder 29, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to son, John Rathbone Oliver, 1891 (Folder 30, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to father, 1889 (Folder 31, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to family, 1889 (Folder 32, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to family, 1890 - 1893 (Folder 33, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to family, 1893 - 1896 (Folder 34, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to family, 1899 - 1900 (Folder 35, Box 59)
      - Robert Shaw Oliver to family, undated (Folder 36, Box 59)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1888 (Folder 37, Box 59)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1889 (Folder 1, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1889 (Folder 2, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1889 (Folder 3, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1890 (Folder 4, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1890 (Folder 5, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, circa 1890 (Folder 6, Box 60)
      - Marion Rathbone Oliver to husband, Robert Shaw Oliver, undated (Folder 7, Box 60)
      - Cora Lyman Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1888 - 1890 (Folder 8, Box 60)
      - Cora Lyman Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, undated (Folder 9, Box 60)
      - Marion Lucy Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1888 - 1889 (Folder 1, Box 61)
      - Marion Lucy Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, circa 1890 (Folder 2, Box 61)
      - John Rathbone Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1890 (Folder 3, Box 61)
      - John Rathbone Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1899, undated (Folder 4, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1888 (Folder 5, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1889 (Folder 6, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1890 (Folder 7, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1892 (Folder 8, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, and family, 1893 - 1894 (Folder 9, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to father, Robert Shaw Oliver, undated (Folder 10, Box 61)
      - Elizabeth Shaw Oliver to brother, John Rathbone Oliver, undated (Folder 11, Box 61)
      - Henry K. Oliver to nephew, Robert Shaw Oliver, 1878 - 1884 (Folder 12, Box 61)
      - Family correspondence, 1889 - 1898 (Folder 13, Box 61)
      - Professional correspondence, 1903 - 1913 (Folder 14, Box 61)
      - Other correspondence, 1864 - 1911 (Folder 15, Box 61)
    - Miscellany, 1887 - 1935; 7.2.2; Boxes: 61 - 63 Folders: 16 - 19, 1 - 16, 1 - 6
      - Invitations from President and Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt, 1904 - 1906 (Folder 16, Box 61)
      - Invitations from President and Mrs. Howard Taft, circa 1909 - 1913 (Folder 17, Box 61)
      - Invitations from the White House, undated (Folder 18, Box 61)
      - Invitations, undated (Folder 19, Box 61)
      - Menus from Fort Orange Club List of signatures on back, including Robert Shaw Oliver, 1892 March 1 (Folder 1, Box 62)
      - Junior Promenade Concert, Yale University List of engagements, 1893 January 25 (Folder 2, Box 62)
      - The Dog Shelter, list of patrons including General Robert Shaw Oliver, managed by Elizabeth Shaw Oliver, 1896 January (Folder 3, Box 62)
      - Dinner Cards, by C.R.R. book of poems, including one by Elizabeth Oliver (Stevens), 1896 October 25 (Folder 4, Box 62)
      - Letter to Fiancée from Charles A.?, undated (Folder 5, Box 62)
      - Note to Robert Shaw Oliver from Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt, undated (Folder 6, Box 62)
      - Balance Sheet for September, 1889 October 3 (Folder 7, Box 62)
      - Hearing before the House Committee on Military Affairs conserving the Army Appropriation Bill, Statement by Robert Shaw Oliver, 1906 January 23 (Folder 8, Box 62)
      - Commemoration of John Paul Jones, 1906 April 24 (Folder 9, Box 62)
      - Testimony of the Secretary of War in the Wood Hearing, circa 1906 (Folder 10, Box 62)
      - Special Passport of Assistant Secretary of War Robert Shaw Stevens, circa 1913 (Folder 11, Box 62)
      - Copy of the will of Robert Shaw Oliver, 1926 June 17 (Folder 12, Box 62)
      - Toboggan slide at Ridgefield, undated (Folder 13, Box 62)
      - Map of Versailles, 1887 (Folder 14, Box 62)
      - Written poem, signed “The Foal”, undated (Folder 15, Box 62)
      - Added Rhymes by William Croswell Doane, undated (Folder 16, Box 62)